## João Felipe Soares

Email: joaofsoares@yahoo.com

**Ph**. +353 83 300 8099

Languages: Portuguese (Native), English (Advanced) and Spanish (Basic)

## **Career Summary**

Work as Java Developer with more than 8 years of experience in Information Technology. Certificated by Oracle on OCP Java SE 7 Programmer. Worked 1 year and half with Linux Support, certified by LPI with LPIC 2 certification, 6 years with JEE, JPA, EJB, RCP, WebLogic, PL/SQL on Oracle 11g and 12c, 1 year and half with Scala(2.11, 2.12), Micro Services, Akka HTTP, Play 2, MySQL and 6 months working with C#. In his free time, he likes to study different technologies as JVM languages, Python, Scala, Big Data (Data Science), Functional Programming and Distributed Systems also reading books related to the subject.

#### **Education and Certifications**

**2016** Specialization in Architecture of Solutions in Technology, DeVry Metrocamp, Campinas São Paulo, Brazil.

2015 Bachelor in Computer Science, Faculdade Anhanguera, Rio Claro, São Paulo, Brazil

2010 Computer Technician, Senac São Paulo, Rio Claro, São Paulo, Brazil

**2018** Functional Programming in Scala Specialization - Coursera - License: WG68RE7AC4SK

**2016** Oracle Certified Professional, Java SE 7 Programmer - ORACLE - License: OC1363764

**2015** LPIC 2 - LPI - License: LPI000201972 (expired Jan 2020)

#### **Technical Skills**

JAVA / J2EE, Scala (Akka, Play 2), Python, Programming & Frameworks C#, PLSQL, Spring, Web Services (Rest, Reactive, WSDL, SOAP), JSON, JavaScript (Angular JS, React JS).

JBoss, Tomcat, Jetty, Eclipse, IntelliJ, Software / Tools VSCode, Jenkins, Redmine, Jira, Maven, SBT, ANT, Design Patterns, Enterprise Architect.

Oracle 11g, 12c, MySQL and VMDS. Databases

Subversion and GIT. Version Control

# **Work History**

#### Airboxlab / Foobot, Dec 2019 - Jun 2020

#### Senior Backend Developer

#### **Foobot**

Developing features to collect air quality data using Reinforcement Learning to calculate the pollutants and how to improve air quality expanding less energy with more accuracy.

- Java, Scala, Python Development
- AWS DevOps
- ETL
- Integration Tests
- Product improvement
- Documentation

**Technologies:** Java 8, Scala, Python, MySQL, Jenkins, AWS(EC2, S3, DynamoDB) Spring 4, JUnit GIT, Maven, Jenkins, Red Hat Linux, Ubuntu Server.

Devoteam. Oct 2018 – Jun 2019 (Luxembourg)

Java/J2EE Developer

#### Société Générale Bank & Trust

#### Liquidity

Developing an application to calculate Bank's liquidity and provide to the Business Analysis team reports being able to change data and fix irregular values.

- Java Development
- Front End Development
- PL/SQL Development (Oracle 12c)
- ETL
- Bug Fix
- Environment configuration
- Documentation

**Technologies:** Java 8, React JS, Oracle 12c, Spring 4, JUnit, GIT, Maven, Jenkins, Red Hat Linux.

e-Spatial Solutions. Dec 2017 - Sep 2018 (Ireland)

### Java/J2EE Developer

# Department of Agriculture, Food and the Marine - LPIS

Developing software customization using iSmart product for the Department of Agriculture, Food and the Marine of Ireland. LPIS is the Department of Agriculture's spatial database that underpins area-based payments to Irish farmers.

- Java Development
- PL/SQL Development (Oracle Spatial)
- GIS (iSmart)
- Environment configuration

Documentation

**Technologies:** Java 8, Oracle 12c, Spring 4, JUnit, SVN, Maven, GIS (iSmart), Bamboo, SonarQube.

#### Suntech do Brasil. Dec 2016 - Aug 2017

### Java/J2EE Developer

- Linux installation, configuration and maintenance
- Deploy process
- MySQL maintenance
- Access Control creation
- Authentication Encryption Library (Scala 2.12 Library)
- Integration with other solutions of the company by services (Scala, Akka HTTP, Java 8, REST and SOAP)

### Multi Configurator Tracker Suntech.

Developing software tools to configure trackers system from Suntech.

- Migration system from VB to Java 8
- Creation of new features
- Bug Fix
- Web services development (Java 8, Spring, REST)
- Unit test development
- Documentation

**Technologies:** Java 8, JPA, Hibernate, SOAP, JUnit, MySQL, GIT, Maven, Scala (Play 2, Akka HTTP, SBT), GIT, Ubuntu Server, Serial Port Configuration.

#### Suntech Cockpit Project.

Developing software to asset management, forecast sales, logistic, general report and stock control.

- Manager meeting to create a new solution and road map
- Software available to Korean team
- Features development
- Bug Fix
- Unit test development
- Documentation

Technologies: React JS, Scala 2.12, Spray, Web Services, MySQL, GIT.

# Suntech Billing Project.

Developing software to control and deliver billing process. Libraries developed in Scala to improve the project performance and features.

- Manager meeting to create a new solution and road map
- Following company rules for each client
- Features development
- Bug Fix
- Unit test development
- Documentation

Technologies: React JS, Java 8, Spring, Web Services, MySQL, GIT.

### Plus IT Consulting. Apr 2016 - Dec 2016

#### Java/J2EE Developer

Canal Conecta Project Kroton Educação.

Developing software tools for education.

- Manager meeting to discuss new features and improvements
- Oracle database maintenance
- Oracle database support on migration version
- Deploy process
- Help support team
- Development of internal and external web services (Java 8, Spring, Scala, Spray)
- Development of encryption system to authentication (Scala Library)
- Unit test development
- Linux configuration and maintenance

**Technologies:** Java 8, JPA, Hibernate, JUnit, HTML 5, Angular JS, Less, Bootstrap, Web Services (Rest and SOAP), Oracle 11g and 12c, Tomcat, JBoss (Wildfly 8), RedHat Linux, Scala (SBT, Play 2), GIT, Maven, Spring, JAX-RS, Google Maps.

### CGI Group. Nov 2015 - Apr 2016

#### **GIS Consultant**

KPIs Project NeoEnergia

Developing software tools for energy electric system using GIS.

- Development of new features on client site
- Validation features and process on client site
- Oracle PL SQL development

Technologies: C#, Visual Studio 2010, ESRI, Oracle 11g, SVN.

Indra Company. Mar 2013 - Nov 2015

#### **Systems Analyst**

### **Vivo Star Project**

Developed software tools for telecommunications system.

- Features development
- Deploy on WebLogic and TomCat
- Bug fix

Technologies: Java 7, PL/SQL, JPA, Spring MVC, Hibernate, JSF, Oracle Weblogic, SVN/GIT.

### **InGRID Project**

Developing software tools for energy electric system using GIS.

- Support N3
- Implementation of new features

Technologies: Java 6, JEE, Java RCP, PLSQL, EJB, JPA, GIS (IGEA), Oracle Weblogic, SVN.

### **InNDM Project**

Developing software tools for energy electric system using GIS.

- Finish project development
- Support implementation
- Meeting with functional team and managers to discuss Go Live process
- Deploy process on WebLogic
- Bug fix

Technologies: Java 6, JEE, Java RCP, PLSQL, EJB, JPA, GIS (IGEA), Oracle Weblogic, SVN.

### Comgás Project - Smallworld GIS

Developing software tools for gas distribution system using GE Smallworld.

- Customized Web tool used by GE Smallworld SIAS
- Documentation of features ordered by the client
- Oracle Database maintenance
- JBoss configuration
- Deploy process

Technologies: Java 7, J2EE, JSF, Smallworld, Magik, PL/SQL, JBOSS, MyEclipse, SVN.

### ATOS. Sep 2012 - Mar 2013

#### **System Analyst**

Developed software tools for CPFL Company using Magik. Smallworld GE Product.

- Development of Magik engine to extract VMDS information to Oracle Database
- Work on database maintenance using PL SQL

Technologies: Magik, Smallworld Electric Office, SVN.

Indra Company. May 2011 - Sep 2012

### **Trainee Programmer**

#### InGRID Project.

Developing software tools for energy electric system using GIS.

- Support N3
- Implementation of new features
- Participated of Go Live period, fixing implementation bugs.

Technologies: Java 6, JEE, Java RCP, PLSQL, EJB, JPA, GIS (IGEA), Oracle Weblogic, SVN.

### InNDM Project.

Developing software tools for energy electric system using GIS.

- Features implementation
- Meeting with functional team to discuss features
- Presentation environment creation
- Linux configuration and maintenance

- Deploy process on WebLogic
- Bug fix

Technologies: Java 6, JEE, Java RCP, PLSQL, EJB, JPA, GIS (IGEA), Oracle Weblogic, SVN.

# SPQR Tecnologia da Informação. Feb 2010 - May 2011

# **Support Analyst**

Support in Linux systems for MicroCPD Company.

- Configuration of MicroCPD systems
- Remote support on applications services (Squid, Iptables, Samba, Apache)
- Installation of the product on client
- Shell Script maintenance and development
- Hardware maintenance

Technologies: CentOS Linux, Shell scripting.